hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Consequence format, and, let's start off then.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The first one is, we are… the development cannot proceed due to lack of data that we're having.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So… the… first of all, we… and there's also some other access issues that we are facing.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So we… I don't think we still have any access to Purser.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And we also don't have any of the sample data that we need to proceed with any of the…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: MLT work, and… Any of the other. So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: This is, decline-dependent, and, this could,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Like, protect how we start the initial pages of the group, basically.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So… The second risk relates to the first one.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: As we do not have the data, there are several different kinds of ML models that we wanted to try, and to see which has the best performance. So, like, the goal of the entire project is to be better than the manual one, but if we do not test the different ML models, we will not have a good enough idea of which to proceed with.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And that just increases the uncertainty a lot.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Third one, I think, is… More of a… future concern. If,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Depending on if we make the… how we make the project, and how…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: whether scope creep does happen, because we've kept it very minimal right now. First of all, because we don't have, we've not gotten our hands dirty yet.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And also because we don't know how the data looks, so that might happen, but this is more of a future concern, rather than something we're facing.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Fourth one is…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the client is pretty much, has strong preferences, and, is pretty much locked into the Azure environment. So, we… we will not be using any tools that, basically
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: has to, like, force them to learn new things that they don't want to learn. And as a consequence, basically, we're, like, making our choices such that we're not using Terraform, we're using Bicep. Alright, is that not making them learn things through the online environment? We can go back, we'll go back over a bit. We'll go back there. And…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The fifth one is not that big of an issue now, but might become one in the future. There could be some schema volatility, depending on,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: If, like, how much, changes we're gonna have to make to the ML output that we get.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And how that goes into films.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay. The rest is just a… my take on…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The risk mitigation strategies we can have for each one of them.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Scheduling calls with basically the client, and, like, sending changes to them so that we get the access to the cursor, and even more importantly than that, that we get access to the data.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Second one, I did write something, but it's mainly just, like, dependent on the first being resolved, so that we can just try out the… I think we have 3 ML candidates, Brittany.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Third one is, we will start missing milestones if, if, we, this continues, and,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you're not able to, like, start work on… well, that's not… scope creep is not… it's different, right?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You may have smart as risk number one. This one, this would be more of a futuristic. I think I should change it and just,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Instead of being scope creep, right? For right now, scope creep is far outside than what we are currently doing. Yeah, scope creep is what? Scope creep would be if you were designing the system, and instead of having
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, a certain number of formats that they expect us to. Okay, sure, sure, okay, yep. They, they, we suddenly decide, or they decide that it would be better if we could handle more. Right.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Or different tech kinds.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Architectural complexity is, is, we have already decided that, when we were talking with them, that we would only do the minimal amount of darkerization, and…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: keep anything, like, open television and such into, like, stress goes, so that we… we're not…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Going to start with the reward.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And this overhead from schema is not relevant. So, so let's look at these one by one, okay? So,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Well, two things. Let's do the risk, all right, and then what I also want to do is sort of share with you
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And I'm actually going to spend this weekend reflecting on it, make sure what I'm sharing is actually correct, but I'll share it anyway. It kind of what…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, what are those kinds of expectations that we would have from a project management perspective?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: by, you know, by soon, by the end of the semester, etc, so you can make sure you queue that stuff up, right? So we'll do that as well. But happy to focus on… on the risk part.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the… So, I'm just gonna give my, like, direct feedback, right? So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Risk one, I think, is actually two different risks here, right? So it's really… there's one about
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: getting, you know, some access to some tooling, and the other is access to the data. Those are… I would… I would put those as two different risks, because
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The… there's a… the consequences are eroded as one consequence, but they are really different consequences.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Depending on… depending on the access. And… and also, potentially, the mitigations for them could be a little bit different as well. But those are actually very legitimate… legitimate risks, right? 100% agree with you there.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Now, let's go to the mitigation for risk number one, and I think… by the way, I also think you did a great job of, sort of, you know, the way you wrote the risks as well. I think it's really well done. If you ever do, sort of, a presentation where you want to show risks, it'll be a lot… need to be a lot less wordy, right?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But having this as the backup is really good. Did a really nice job there.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, if I think about… Just in general, about risk.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Risks and how to… how to manage their risks.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: there's…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: how do you… you know, there's multiple ways to attack risks, right? One, we can just say, okay, good, no problem, all of it, right? But that's not what you want to do here. You can…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: mitigate risks, right? What does it mean… what does it mean to mitigate a risk? Let me ask that question. What does that really mean?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I mean, so to mitigate the effects of a risk, so it doesn't negatively impact our team or our project? Okay, right. There's also something where you could reduce the likelihood of something occurring. Those are two different things, right? So one is, hey, it may occur in one of the impact, and the other's a likelihood. So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, schedule the 30-45 minute meeting, right? What is that? Is that really a mitigation, or is that a reduced likelihood of it occurring?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I guess it would be reduced likelihood, because even after the meeting, there's still a chance that, you know, no further…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: What would reduce… what would be an example of, like, a reduced, sort of, impact if it… if it does happen?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And I don't care about, like, the fine… you know, I don't care about the nuances, this, reduced likelihood or reduced impact, but we should think about… we should… when we think about a risk, we should think about both of those, right, because they're both strategies.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That we can employ. Sometimes we can do one, sometimes we can do the other, sometimes we can do both.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So what might be, A way to reduce impact.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Wait to release… it's not to wait for the, like, the…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: A large amount of data to come in and just ask them for, like, a much smaller amount, and then just kind of go with that first.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That would reduce… like, there would still be an impact, because we would not be able to, like, train any exploratory models, but we would kind of get a feel of what the data is structured like, or what are, like, the usual entries in some of them.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And anyone else?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think for the cursor issue, it might be that we can use our own
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: LLMs to help us, like, we currently are, without using clients' proprietary data. Just to, like, we can hold off working on the proprietary data, like, we don't have any… You don't have the data, so whatever reason? So, yeah, right now we're using our own LLM, so that part is, I guess, currently being mitigated.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: As for the data, I'm not sure what we can do, like, we need something from them.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: is there any way to… you know, so I realize that for those sort of machine learning models, you really want to see the data from them, but for a lot of the other work… so…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: There's a…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Ideally, you'd be in a situation, and I certainly remember from your requirements document, where you were trying to…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I forget what… I forget which quality attribute you called it. Was it extensibility? I can't remember, or you need to, you know… you're doing this for three types of data sources, and it needs to be relatively simple to add a fourth, a fifth, a sixth on, right? There's… there's something there.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: is there any way to use synthetic data?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Like, just… you know what? You go… Because, cause, yes.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: that's not gonna… But then you have to know the format, right? Yeah, so you're gonna make something up, right? You're gonna make… you're gonna… again, I'm just throwing an idea out there, right? You totally make it up, right? Because that training part is just a piece of the whole… the whole pipeline, right? So there's probably a lot you can do.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And you may need to do some rework, sure, but there's probably a bunch that you can do, even if you don't know… you don't have any real data.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And it's not uncommon in…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, getting data sometimes is very, you know, doesn't happen quickly, and there's a lot of times where people need to sort of make some forward progress, even before they have it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Not ideal, I understand, but I think also.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You raised the point. You know, I think you… it was, maybe there's just a little bit of data we can get, right? So, maybe define what that, you know, sort of minimally viable amount of data is.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, it will sufficiently unblock you, so you can make some more forward progress. So, actually, we don't even need the data, we just need the schema, and then we need this makeup data. That's the main problem. So, we don't even need this small amount of data. Okay. Yeah, so all we require right now is the basic schema of how the data would look like in a table.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And then we would be able to work on the pipeline, and they would be able to work on the MX modeling as well.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: PDFs or some input files to start on the admission part? Well, you don't need that, because the PDFs are only for the OCR part. Like, okay, you're… okay, then you get access… can you get an account and pretend that you're buying something on their website, and go look at some of the data that is available, and make up a schema to start with?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right? You know, you know, what is it? It's all the parts information, right? It's all the data about…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah, I did write a little about representative data, so that could be something. In this case, it would be, like, just going onto their website and just scraping a few pages, I guess.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That would be better than, you know, not detecting. It's not going to eliminate the risk, sure, but it certainly will help mitigate the risk.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Mitigate the impact of the risk.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And I think a lot of it is also just around, sort of, the… again, you're probably doing all this, but…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, being very…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, up front with the custody, with the client, and saying, you know, not just like, hey, we need this data, but…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: here are the… here, you know, we need it by this date, here's the impact if we don't have it by this date. Just being very…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, very explicit, and whenever you meet with them, you know, here are the actions, the open actions is the item number one you ever review in your meetings.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think, for the last meeting, I wrote to them, I mentioned that we are currently blocked, and the response we got was, you should be getting the data by end of yesterday.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So I'm thinking if I write a follow-up mail today, or, like… Yeah, yeah, you know. Like, I've chased them twice in, like, two days, so… Let's say, hey, this is great, we're, you know, we were hoping to get the data yesterday, as you mentioned, and maybe something came up.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Please let us know when we can expect it, because we're really looking forward to, you know.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: people never want to hear, we're blocked, we're blocked, we're blocked, right? And that doesn't mean you're not, right? But…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Because it's kind of like the impression people get is that
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: oh, we're, you know, we're not doing… we're sitting like this until you give us the data, which you're not doing. So, just, you know, be more…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, we're eager to, you know, we're at the point where we really could leverage that data and what we're, you know, giving them today.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Other kind of things you could do is… I'm actually referring to a listing right here.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know what, that's not going to help the end government. I think we talked about most of them.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But the other… the other thing in risks is that…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And it's hard to do this for all risks. Some risks you can sort of say.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: kind of a leading indicators, so…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: If, you know, if you're seeing that.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you're a week away, you know, you don't want to wait till it's the last minute. I need it by this date and ask for it the day before, right? But you can start raising
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the yellow flag, and then the red flag as you get closer and closer to those, you know, sort of must-have dates. Because obviously the…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The impact increases.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: As you, you know, the more you… the closer you get.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Let me sit here. So if I… and I actually made a list here. If you're thinking about a sort of a mitigation plan overall,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: There's kind of four… four elements to a fantastic… to a great mitigation plan.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: One is what you're doing… we talked about most of these. What you're doing to try to prevent it from happening, right? Try to prevent the risk
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: From materializing, preventing the risk from becoming an issue.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right, because it's… at some point, Fair enough.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You're putting this as a risk?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Is this already an issue?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, and what is the impact of that issue? There's two… there's a difference. A risk is something that may happen. An issue is something that actually has occurred, and it is impacting you already.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: what you're trying to do… what you're going to do if the risk does materialize to reduce the negative impact, that would be kind of a second part of a really good mitigation strategy.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: A third one would be…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: what are those leading indicators? How do you know that it's going to become… going to… this risk is going to materialize?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, for example, in this case, if you were in a situation where the customer's usually… the client's usually pretty responsive.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right. If your experience is…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: client is really not responsive in general, it takes them weeks to get back to us, then that leading indicator would change under those two circumstances, right? One would be…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: well, if the client says they're going to get it to us, that's pretty good, right? You know, we're not so worried about it. We can wait till 48 hours before it becomes an issue to raise the flag. If it's something we have a very non-responsive client, then you may want to say, well, we're going to raise that flag, it's going to go from yellow to red, say.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Two weeks before you really need it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And the last is what, you know, if… if you don't get it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: or you don't get it, but when you need it, what is… what are you going to do about it? How are you going to manage it?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So… But those are… it's a really good risk, right? The only thing I would say is…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Break the two, and sort of the caution is that there may be, you know.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Risks typically have a kind of a trigger date, and…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You need to… if there is one here, if there isn't one.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right? If there is one, that really needs to be communicated with the client.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: All right.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Does that all make sense? It does. Okay, no problem.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Beginning.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Go to the next one.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, having manual workloads.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Currently, we cannot proceed on this, but…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The risk that, that I foresee is that
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: until we have, like, some of the ML models trained up and we start exploring.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: There would be a lot of,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: A lot of comparisons that we have to do against the baseline, and we need to, like, really confirm that
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Our demo models that we do pick end up being better than what they currently have.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So this is, like, a tech… is this a technical risk? Yes. Okay. Alright. So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So the… I think I would need to change these a little bit. It's not a mitigation, but…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: One of the indicators we would push to establish is, like, we would have a baseline that they… that we get from their side, where, like, how much time it's taking them, what's their average rate of being correct on the prediction that they have.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And then… we'll… go from our side and see what our machine learning or AI is giving.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And then, you know, what's the… is the confidence scoring robust or not?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And… Is it working properly with the human in the root system, I think?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So… Is this a… It… How is this different?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: than any other… Type of…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Project, or that is doing any type of, sort of, categorization or classification.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Based on ML. Wouldn't he have exactly the same set of circumstances?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, you've got some… you've got some minimal acceptable rates, right? You're going to establish a baseline, you're going to verify it, you're going to…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the… yeah, that's true in almost every case, but here, most of the time you have a defined architecture that you want to go with, like, but here we do not know. We're gonna have to pick between three of them.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So that was why I wrote this one, so that we know that there is some uncertainty among the choices, and how that would affect how we go about it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, how did… I guess maybe I just didn't understand that. So how… so for your three options, how are you going in?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Where in that mitigation do you refer to those three options?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That would just be the minimum credible AI standard for, like… So when, when we're,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Testing all three, we would pick the one that has the appropriate, like, performance and, like, resources usage that they said, and then we would just pick one that does actually exceed the baseline.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay, so really what you're doing is you're reducing your technical risk, by…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: by running… by basically running experiments against three different techniques, right? So that… that's…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That's how… that's how you're… if I understand, that's how you're really mitigating the risk, is that right? Okay, now that makes a lot of sense.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: reading the… reading that, I don't get that? I… I should have, written all three, like, BERT, and… So tech… techno-risk, I'm saying, is one of the… one of the standard ways to mitigate technical risk is by experimenting, and…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: when you do experiments, and I think you're reading that you're on the right path, it's really important to
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: make sure that you design… design the experiment well, right? So here are the… these are the criteria… these are criteria by which we are going to effectively evaluate those different experiments.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah, like, another part to this is that
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The… the manual baseline itself is not established yet. We did ask them during the client meetings, and they were… themselves did not have, like…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: they've categorized enough data, of course, but they don't have a baseline for what they do have, like, they've not done that analysis yet. So that's a part of the risk that we don't have something already to compare against. It will have to be a process between us and them so that we actually have something concrete to compare against.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right, but you could still compare against… you're still going to have some…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: absolute numbers, right? Your experiments are going to provide
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Well, your experiments are going to provide some, you know, automation…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You're gonna know how… let's put it this way, let's say… let's say you run through 100 different, you know, you have each system running through 100 different inputs, yeah.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You're going to know the…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the percentages of those that you have high confidence in need, you know, do or do not need human correction. Yes. Right?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, in some sense.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you're going… you know, that… you're going to know which perform… you know, which one has better performance, right? And I realize it's not going to necessarily tell you, are you saving enough time overall, right? Is it a… but…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You could still… quantitatively evaluate
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Even without all that information. And honestly.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You could, you could, you could…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, do a lot of work before you know what this magic number is.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You don't need that magic number yet.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think 3 is not… What, it's not currently, pressing for us.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So 3's not… 3's not a risk. Tell you why. So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And this is… you're not… every single…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: 80% of every studio and practical team has this… something like this as a risk.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And then during the presentations, you can tell the different faculty members kind of get into arguments with one another.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Is that a risk? No, it's not a risk. I don't think it's a risk. So, I'm gonna head it off with the pass, because I don't think it's a risk. There may be other faculty members who do, and here's why, is that…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: There has never been a project since the
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The world saw its first project that didn't have scope creep as a potential… Issued.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And… It's almost like saying, Well, my project may fail.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I may not succeed, that's a risk.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: It's this, it's just… it's very vague. You don't…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, how do you… how would you mitigate scope of creep? You would do it through good software engineering practices.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So you'd have…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: a scope of agreement with the client. You might have a signed-off statement of work. You might have a, you know, an explicit, sort of, as part of your requirements, an out-of-scope list of things that are out of scope.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You probably might have some change control processes, so if you are
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: If something new comes in, this is the process that you follow in order to determine if that is something you can accept or not.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you're gonna follow, you know, Moscow, for… to understand what, you know, in terms of prioritization of requirements.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So it's just a… it's just part of every project, and software engineering practices will address that for you. Okay. Make sense?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think because we're a newer team, and all of us are kind of new to, like, doing the whole process ourselves.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I did not consider it, like, that there were mature solutions, like, that people actually have done this, like, a thousand times. Yeah, again, it's… but you… but you know some of this already, so you know about creating, like, the statement of work for your… Yes, and the… You know about creating Moscow.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you may not know about, like, a, you know, like a change control thing. You may not know about that, right? But…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But think about… What you would…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: What you would do if, you know, the client said, Well… Here's an example.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: My father, many, many, many, many years ago, was doing a master's in mechanical engineering, and at that time, master's, you write a whole pretty significant thesis, and
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: He spent, you know, huge amounts of time on this thing, you know, thousands of hours on this thing, and he came up with this long, you know, this paper, right, this published paper. And his advisor looks at it, and he said, this is great work.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Now I want you to do it using complex numbers, not just, like, real numbers.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And that was scope creep, right? That was, like, real scope creep. And…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: There wasn't any way to address it other than my father saying, I'm done, and I'm out of here. I don't care about the semesters anymore.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But think about how you would handle a situation where someone… a client would say, well, we really want… we love this, but you want… we want you to do it with… with, with complex or imaginary numbers, right? You would need to say.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay, you don't say no, right? You don't say, no, that wasn't part of our scope. You say.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That's a great idea! That's really interesting. Let us… that wasn't part of our original agreement, or statement of work. Let's go back and understand, do a high-level scoping among ourselves to understand what… how big is this?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: and what its impact would be on the rest of the project, and we'll come back to you, and we'll have that discussion, right? And that's the way to handle it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think right now, I'm not sure if we have an official scope of work.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Is that something we should… You should do, yeah, you should definitely do that. Yeah, I actually think, like, something this client signs off on is really valuable.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay, get an official scope of work, and…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: How we would handle changes. Yeah, yeah, okay.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That's my list here. I think, what you said is much better than what I had for the mitigation of all this, so we'll just, I'll just change it to what you just said. Yeah, but I would… I would not include it as a risk. Okay. It's just part of your…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: part of your project management process. It would just be a doo-do for us to, like, get the official scope of work and, like, changes. Yeah, people don't like seeing, you know, a risk that is just, you know, well, another… another very common risk that people… students often have is
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Well, someone's gonna… You know, Someone's gonna get sick.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right? Well, yeah, someone's probably going to get sick at some point.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But you, as part of your…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: how you manage your project, your project management practices, need to understand and address how you're going to handle if someone gets sick. Is there… are you going to make sure that everyone has a backup person who understands what they're doing? Are you going to build some buffer into your schedule to account for the fact that
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: someone is going to get sick, right? And it is… it's gonna… hopefully none of you, it's gonna be other teams, right? But someone's gonna get sick and be out for a week or two. It happens. So, plan for it, don't call it a risk, right? Okay. Okay.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay, just one… make it loud briefly.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Remove risk 3 and just make it a 2.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The fourth one is just,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah, this is the one that you said you wanted to talk about more, so that they're, they don't, need to learn more than they, than they think they will need to, so that… so I'd just like to get your thoughts. So what's the difference between this and a… and a constraint? Because you have constraints, and you're…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: requirements document. How's it different?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Specifically, that, when we are doing some of the work, there's more, much more,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: documentation or support for one of them, and since it's not an official constraint, right? We might really prefer to use something, but since they themselves are not defining it as an official constraint, so that's why I just kept it. Like, if it was an officially, like.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: They just said that, we would really, like, it has to be in Azure, and, like, you cannot, like, just use Spice for this, then that would… I would not have kept this. But you've got to use Azure, right? Yeah, but, that's a… I think that… isn't that a constraint?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: they just strongly imply that you should use Azure, and you should use Bicep, and you should try to stay away from, like, languages that they give two, three languages that they really use for. So I would… I would try to just move that over to the project constraints. Yeah, yeah. And, you know, every…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Every place you're ever going to be has a… oh, not every place, most places, over 95% of the places out there are going to have constraints like that.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, it's very rare that
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, there are some companies where they say, well, you're… you team… you team, you have responsibility for the entire… you can decide what technologies, you can decide, because you build it and you own it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right? You have to maintain it's not… not my problem that no one else in the company understands Dolang. You do, you know, that's so… that is very, very rare.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yep, and funny enough, they did mention that do not do it in Golang or anything like that, right, that's why I said, yeah, I remember that.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think, because, of course, we're not…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: gonna be responsible for after the handoff, and they'll have to do all the maintenance. I'll just move this to constraints.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And… schema volatility, I think Arjun mentioned something about when we were talking with them, that
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That when… depending on how the… what kind of input we get, and then how the models run, there might be changes that we need to, like, do.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And that we… we're… we're just not aware of how to… it's gonna be in advance, even though we… we can't present how the workflow goes, but this is, actually just a… this is a known, known that… that we do know we'll have to face, so I will just go to the…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: mitigation.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: We could, go with, like, I just wrote, like, a semantic matches, so even if some of the attributes are, like, varying between categories, but they mean the same thing, we could have, like, an additional layer on top that we're just automatically handling it, instead of us going and, like, manually changing it correctly.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Just that I did not add much more complexity.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: It does, but, this is, this is in case that it does happen. Like, a new, kind of format, a new kind of, like, data source comes up, and, this is an automated approach. It does add additional complexity to it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, is there any other sort of mitigation that you could think of doing? So, as an example, I'm not going to actually say what it is, but is there something that could help you
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: understand if this risk is going to manifest itself to an issue earlier, right? The earlier you know about this, the better.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Is there anything you can do to help learn if it's going to be an issue earlier?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Right now, it does not seem likely, from what they have told us. So, that's why this is, I would say, the least of, like, that's a risk 5 in my list. It's likelier to happen.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: We're going to get some metrics from them of the last schema changes, or offering some numbers that are going to predict future. And then the other thing about the risk was if you really want to talk about likelihood of occurrence.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And then the impact, if it does, so people can really understand, hey, this is…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, this sounds like it may be low… maybe low likelihood, potentially significant impact. Yes.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And, you know, you have to decide, okay, how much time you're gonna invest in
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, upfront mitigation on that, or versus something that is going to be, you know, high impact, high likelihood, as an example, right? Yeah, I think I should have mentioned that, at least, because all the other ones are high likelihood… must high likelihood than this. This is something that's…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Like, for comparison, the first risk is, like, high likelihood, because it's… it's, like, definite likelihood, because it's actually doing it late, and, like, very high impact as well, because we cannot…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: do a lot of the stuff that we do. So it's an issue already. It is, it is, yeah. And this is, low impact, but it can be very significant if, like, a large, like, 30-40% of the data we're encountering is, like, does not match what we expect, then we can… we would have to be forced to build this on top, and then to make it… make sure the percentages are on…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, I will change it so that it mentions that it's a low likelihood, but it has significantly. Okay. Yeah, this is a good list. This is what we did.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Suitable to make anyone.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Oh.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, then we can, this is all for,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: This is all for the risk portion, so I'll just go into the project management portion of the document.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So… It's basically from now to, like, May 4th.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And how we're gonna at least,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Have the temporary structure that we have.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Or, like, going through it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, we're currently still in Phase 1 and 2.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, we're still making our SES, and work for MVP has not even started yet.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: There is an initial draft for, like, requirements and architecture.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But they will be finalized when, you know, the… during the next phases.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: After that, during the latter part of the…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: semester, basically, it will be more focused on making sure our work is
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Going smoothly, and evaluating all the progress we have made through there, till the end of this semester, at least.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So what… do you have any plans for, like, what you'll be doing for the next two semesters… two semesters after that?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Other vacations.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: interviews.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: No, it's only for the Spring 2006 roadmap. I've not, actually gone through for the summer roadmap. And have you defined what vertical slices 1 and 2 are?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Vertical slices 1 and 2 are just basically… the first vertical slice would be, all the way up till, like, using our SES to, like, create a MVP.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And two is just, like, all the documentation work that we're gonna do, all the,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Stuff that, would be useful for someone to learn it after the handoff, or even when we're explaining it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Is this too… is this too aggressive?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Given that you have two more semesters.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And given that you're working 12, you know, 12 hours a week this semester.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I will admit that I've gone pretty aggressive, but I think even Arjun is in agreement that if this was a normal semester, then
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: we would not… I would not have pushed this so hard, but…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: with AI, at least my… this is my personal opinion, that as soon as we have the SES and schema and all that stuff.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: like, well-defined enough, it would just be a… it would… it would just enter into a very fast iteration process, see if it works, like, are the tests going properly, are the outputs as we expect? And, I… in my original opinion, should go pretty fast, as soon as we do have that baseline set up.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I don't know, that's… I don't know what we'll do afterwards, whether there's, like, stretch goals or something, but I could be completely wrong. Maybe it takes us, like, deep into the summer or something, but this is what happened.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Is that… so, the question… again, it's not… not this week or next week, right? But at some point.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You will want to have, before your end of semester, like, what your
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: entire plan is, right, for including the other semesters. Okay.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, these are, how,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think the responsibilities should be split.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, currently, for the project lead, she's the team leader, and, we've still yet to determine how the structure will rotate and
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: how, like, how long the rotation structure should be? So, should it be… Oh, we… we were actually talking with the other teams. I think they were rotating per month basis, the team leaders. We didn't want to do it so early, but we thought we could do it every mini. Every what? Every mini-sam. So, like, after the spring break, we get a new…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Team lead? Yeah.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And then, so everyone gets, like, two, I think, two rotations of…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And I just said, there's no right or wrong, right? As long as you have a reason for making that decision, right? That's all that matters.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah, monthly, we might be… too fast. It sounds nice, but there's no continuity.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Architecturally, well, everyone is responsible for knowing, because this is a small team, everyone must know the entire architecture, so that they know how everything is going, but…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So the person who is, like, most in-depth with it, and most, like, you know, responsible for it would be designated as an architecture lead.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: As for the data and ML lead, it's just basically the one who goes most, like, hands-on and, like, you know, is responsible for debugging it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the… and… engineering lead, that's the one I mostly fear about, because
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: we all have to own the implementation. It's… it cannot be any other way, I think. And… because engineering lead and QA, it has to be done by all of us, basically, so I'm not sure whether I should keep it, or… Well, I think… so…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, again, this is more… maybe a quality discussion.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But… You know, you're…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, I don't know if it's the architecturally, but there's certainly someone who… you all own… you all own implementation, sure.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But there may be times where there's someone who has
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, has more of a…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Consult, you know, people consult with them, they have more of, sort of, a tech lead type of
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: responsibility, right? So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: QA process lead, I think, is… you absolutely need one, because how… who… who has that response… yes, I'm gonna go… I'm gonna go test. Who has the responsibility for the over quality plan for our system?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: to make sure, and when I say quality plan, I don't just mean that our software is high quality, it's that we are
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: We are doing what we said we are going to do with respect to how we are operating.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So… you know, co- gets checked in, it…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, here's an example. Someone who's actually may go and
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Look at data around how many, how many… Review, code reviews.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Are actually providing meaningful… meaningful comments that are provided to them, versus ones that are just like, you know, okay, just pass it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, it's typically someone who, like, who's…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Looking, sort of, one level deeper.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Into the… into the processes, and everyone has that responsibility, right?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah, I think you're right. Otherwise, we might fall into, like.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the team's gonna do it, and then no one ends up doing it. No one's gonna do metrics tracking unless there's someone else responsible for metrics tracking. Yeah, so we can have a discussion, like, who has the most experience for, like, for the engineering lead, who has the most experience for, like,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: You know, working with pipelines and integrations and stuff, we'll just assign that person.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: As per the QA lead.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: It's gonna have to be somewhat strict so that, you know, they actually kind of, like, go deep into it and, like, see that it's all we need.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So, we'll have… we'll… we'll discuss.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And you want to have names, even though you're going to be changing, make sure there's people's names on those. Yeah, definitely. I think, yeah, whenever we write theme, then we're kind of, like, it becomes the chinx, and then sometimes it ends up not being done, so…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Success criteria is just basically, from the data metrics and product metrics, so percentages of records that are deemed high confidence and are actually high confidence. They're true positives instead of being false positives.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: We could also do some confidence distributions at the, if we go that deep.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: What are defect rates? Is the…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: After we give all this to the client, and they start checking our work.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Is the post-approval rate what we have.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And is the human in the loop? That… I'll have to add that. Human in the loop part… portion where it comes from.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Alright.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: This is, the research planning is pretty weighed still.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Actually, the human allocation portion is much more weight than the AI portion. We've not decided how to fill all the roles yet, and how they're… if… and if they're gonna be rotated. Like, we've decided that the leadership… team lead will be rotated, but what about the other one? Should we just have one person
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: throughout the project, who's responsible for QAns.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: AI resources is basically all the things like cursor that we're gonna leverage.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And how it's gonna basically handle all the… Coding and the repetitive tasks.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Like, boxing the PDFs.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But, the last portion is basically about what… what is our, like, responsibility at the end of it all, like, we are responsible for validating it, whether we… assessing risk, like, whether we should even use it for certain portions or not, or whether it's best handled by us.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And then…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the last thing that I wrote is, like, being very cautious that no proprietary data is not, like, going through
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: other AI tools than what they can use.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Finally, yeah.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: how we're gonna do our task planning? So, ETVX is the one that, is most, like, familiar for me. This might change depending if the team decides that this format website does not work for us.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Domain ownership is another thing that will come up in the… when we make the human rows, basically, assignments, and…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Work will then be distributed.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Based on how people, you know, tell about their… which domain they're most familiar and comfortable with.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The information criteria is… We will have, like, verification steps there.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: we go through.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And, as per the non-core artifacts.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: the… that would… that is a much more subjective process. We'll have, like,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Hopefully, we'll have checklists that we'll just go through to confirm that they meet standards.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And… As for progress tracking…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That's something that, I think the QA lead will have to, oversee, and,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: We'll have to see how our… how much time we are taking on each of our, like, sprints, or…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: What, what the metrics are for backlog sizes, and…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Are we reworking too much, or…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: spending too much time on, like, other things that, we initially said would not be spending that much time. Right, so that's actually helpful, so you can look at… that's actually a really good thing for, you know, a two-way process that you can do, is, like, is…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: A very mature team, and there aren't many teams that do this, goes and says, you know, says, this is how we plan to spend our time, and then actually measures how they spend their time and reflects on that.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: This is all I have, and let's just for my, this is the risk and the project. Let me share one thing with you. I should put something up.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I'll get that in the back of here, because I can't plug that into this laptop. I think I've got to do that.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yes.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think… I can move it, it's not gonna read you. Throughout so long.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Alright.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay, I'll put it here, too.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So I'm going to send this to you. I want… I'm going to spend this weekend reviewing it, though, because I just, like, wrote it yesterday, so I haven't really had time, so much time to look at it myself.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I don't need this stuff right down here. Let's probably a bit more about this. So trying to really think about
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: your semester.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And give you some guidance as to
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: What types of things may be expected, you know, or…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And every project is different, right? But what kinds of things
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: should either exist, or be in progress, or thinking about, what's maybe coming up soon, what things… hey, you're probably not going to have this yet, but these are things that you'll probably need at some point, right? So…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, context diagram, the vision, understanding of requirements and notional architecture. None of this should be huge.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, I guess scope, agreement, statement of work are probably pretty… I'm just gonna put those together here.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: As you can tell, I wrote this… I didn't have a whole lot of time to work on it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Come on, there we go.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: The semester roadmap, we talked about, you know, you showed that, your process definitions, that's really important this time.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And any external dependencies, risk identification, which you're doing, the change management, which is something we talked about today, like, what happens when there is… when there is change.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And I guess I should also put here, you know, sort of your…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: what do we call it? Software engineering? What do you call software engineering? SCS. What? SCS, Software Engineering. System.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: SES? Yeah. Okay.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: That should be theirs here, right?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And then, you know, as you're getting more, you know, more understanding, you're going to create your breakdown structure, you're going to start to populate your backlog, and understand what your milestones are going to be, what your milestone plan is. And then, once you have that, you can really start working on
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, your… your, sorry, your work package, your release plans, your… start really having your backlogs, and…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: If you're going to be doing, earned value charts and things like that. And then… and I actually wrote at the end that full ceremony execution, you know, at some point, people are saying, okay, we're going to follow…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Scrum, for example, right? Or we're gonna follow…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: milestone-driven execution, and as a part of that, there's a bunch of different ceremonies that one does, right? So at some point, you're gonna evolve where, hey, this is our… this is how we operate, this is the cadence
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: This is how we operate as a team, and this is the cadence of work that we do. You know, every… every week we do this, every two weeks we do that, every three weeks we do that.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: So that's just… I'll share this, you don't need to copy it, but this could be helpful
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: in terms of trying to understand the expectations, not to… well, two things. One is the expectations of the program, but also
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Is used as a guide to try to help, you know, yourselves. Kind of, are you on track with things related to program management as well?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Does that make sense? Alright.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah, I just want to do… I just need to do a,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: sync between what I thought of and what's in the
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: program documents to make sure that I'm in alignment. So, I'll do that this weekend and get it out to you.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah, I think, again, I think your team's doing great. I think you've got… it's a great start in project management work.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: If you look at this list of items, you're either, you know, you have or you're well on your way for many of them.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: so… I don't think certain things are going pretty well.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And I was very impressed.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: by the risks.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Seriously. I've seen a lot of bad risk registers before, okay? That's pretty good.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Anything else I can help you with?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I think…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: we'll just take your, like, the… because a lot of the risks that, I think need to be changed, like, be more in line with your feedback, and then at least two of them, or, like, one of them needs to be removed, and I'll just change the other ones.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Yeah. And part of your process would be, for example, okay, one… you can decide however you want to do it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But… Because we're talking about risks.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Well, at our sprint reviews, we review our risk register, or at our… like, one thing that teams sometimes do is they create a risk register. Why? Because they need to show it at their end of semester presentation.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And it's unfortunate, right? It gets… yes, you get practice doing it, but it's not something that actually helps you in your program. And I realize this is very… it's not a giant project, so you can keep all those risks in your head.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But in a much larger project, you may have
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: 25, 30 items, and you may want… need to review them and look at, hey, what is becoming
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know, for… I've been in situations where, for a given risk, I say, okay, what… as a team, when do we need to review this risk?
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: And we set a trigger, so it could be…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: two-year project. It could be we want to review it in 2 weeks, could be we want to review it in 3 months.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: who needs to be involved in that review? So there's a lot of ways… there's a very basic risk register, but you can get a lot more sophisticated around them, too, and use it to more active… actively develop a period project.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Okay, well, cool.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Hope everyone has a good weekend. I'm gonna go to my… I have the next team right now, so I'm gonna go try again.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: It's already Friday, so… it's amazing, isn't it? Alright.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: 282. Thank you for the,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: But the power here is very nipple. I mean, my laptop thinks you too.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Thank you. Alright, thanks.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Thank you so much,
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: you know… Shamash.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Dude, I said all your stuff about, like, how close by speed we expect. Hopefully, that turns out something good.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: we can only start speeding up after this semester. You won't have the shit till the end of the semester. When you start developing, it'll be about money. Not even give, like, freaking Cadbury to…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: 2 months.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Hey, motherfucker, you're the team lead. When I'm team lead, everyone's getting cat buried, don't worry. Let's see.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Cadbury things. I get you guys.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Here.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: I have the… I noted on some minutes. We have another meeting, right? Yeah.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: What? Fine. Do you want to, lead that one? Yeah.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: Hey, you're only reading it. No, I'm done for the days and night. But you don't have any content! Hey, yeah, no one has content. Yeah. We don't know what we're reading. We have to make content right now. Yeah, you have 3 hours, right? Start.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: By the way, what have you talk… I mean, he's the AI coach, right? Yeah, software engineering, this thing. That's what you're… I think the analyst is only. You just have to pass over whatever you're gonna use AI. Yeah, yeah. Last two pages, man, I made in, like, last 10 minutes. Thank God it did not focus. He just… that's why I just kept going on the spread, because that's what I remembered as, like, 3 pages, I'll just…
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: keep reviewing them. You made this yesterday itself. This one I made yesterday, but Rishi told me, like, just before meeting… Project one was the same. This, like, project part is… so I added two parts that I could defend, so I… all of this was cut, dude. Like, when I was actually copying from the AI that part, right? Because, of course, I cannot try it and test it.
hrishikb@andrew.cmu.edu: It gave, like, 5-10 pages of content. I cut it down to, like, 2 so that I could extend. Forward to stop the routing?